Hamish Tennent

Blending methods from UX, research, industrial and product design to discover how new technologies can create futures where humans have better relationships with each other and technology. Born in Aotearoa New Zealand, previously working in San Francisco and New York, currently based in Taipei.

Open for opportunities, get in touch if you'd like to connect.

HT @ mynameishamish.com (+1) 415 767 8322 www.mynameishamish.com

Currently: Recently moved to Taipei, Taiwan

Experience

Senior UX Design Technologist

Volkswagen Group of America, Bay Area California- Fall 2018 - Winter 2021

Our US based team was the global lead for Volkswagen Group's Inclusive Mobility Initiative to partner with disability advocacy and community rights groups and provide the research and design link between them and product engineering teams in order to design future self driving vehicles to be as inclusive as possible. Project sprints would be spun up for 2-6 month time frames around specific; engineering impact points (ie car seating arrangement), disability rights groups (ie work with Lighthouse for the Blind to make sure a new vehicle was accessible to blind or low vision users), or topics (ie wheelchair access and securement into a specific vehicle). In my time there I worked as designer, team lead, technologist, researcher on a wide array of project topics. This involved working at all levels of a project, from detailed design work to securing new project funding, project management and delivering results into the engineering pipeline such that it can successfully become part of the vehicle engineering process.

User Experience Designer/Visiting Professor

Cornell University, New York (Information Science Department) - Fall 2016 - Fall 2018

Designing the UX for robotics in the field of academic research. Conducting design focused research in the Human Robot Interaction and interactive devices space, focused on group and social dynamics. Specific research looking at how to better understand user experiences and perceptions of sound, expressive and non-verbal behaviours and social dynamics with social robotics and interactive devices.

User Experience Designer

Stanford University, Bay Area California (Centre For Design Research) - Spring 2015 - Fall 2016 ID and UX designer who designed and implemented hardware and software tools for autonomous vehicle and social robotics research. Published research in journals and conferences on the perceptions of both domestic robots and autonomous cars. Lead a number of workshops for 20+ people on design skills such as sketching, video making and prototyping. Ran cross cultural research of previous lab work in Europe.

Hardware User Experience Designer (contractor)

Facebook, Bay Area California - Summer 2016

Working as a contract UX designer on a new hardware project. Worked primarily using a design through research approach to designing the UX of emerging tech products. Methods used included; Role play, Wizard of Oz and contextual interviewing of participants as well as designing and conducting research studies into existing market products. Research was to uncover social expectations, norms and where value could be found in new multi-modal interfaces.

Industrial Designer

Sparse, Bay Area California - Summer 2014 - Summer 2015

Working on a number of different Industrial Design and softwoods projects aimed at the urban cyclist. Took a number of bicycle accessory projects through to production and worked as a team on a number of softwoods projects. Primary skills include concept generation and exploration and creating production ready CAD files.

Audi Innovation Research (AIR) Fellow. 2013. Fellowship to develop UX concepts for 2050.

Prop builder. Gyro Constructivists. 2012. Projects for the Hobbit, Avatar, Cadbury. Variety of movie, tv, public installation projects.

Industrial designer. Hygiene Systems. 2011 - 2012. Mostly pre-manufacturing design and redesign of existing products. Worked as one of two designers on a team of 12 engineers.

Education

California College Of The Arts. 2013 - 2015.
MFA In Design (Interaction Design)

Massey University - New Zealand. 2008 - 2011.
BDes Industrial Design - 1st Class Honours

San Jose State University. 2010 - 2011.
Bachelor Of Industrial Design - 1 Year Exchange

Select Publications

Tennent, H., Shen, S., & Jung, M. (2019, March). Micbot: A peripheral robotic object to shape conversational dynamics and team performance. In 2019 14th ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction (HRI) (pp. 133-142). IEEE.

Tennent, H., Lee, W. Y., Hou, Y. T. Y., Mandel, I., & Jung, M. (2018, October). Paperino: Remote wizard-of-oz puppeteering for social robot behaviour design. 2018 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (pp. 29-32).

Moore, D., **Tennent, H,** Martelaro, N. & Ju, W. (2017, March). Making noise intentional: A study of servo sound perception. 2017 ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction (HRI (pp. 12-21). IEEE.

Teaching + Workshops

SXSW Panelist

'The Sound of Robots' panel at SXSW 2017.

Cornell University

Co-taught Human Robot Interaction and Rapid Prototyping class (Spring and Fall 2017).

California College Of The Arts

Teaching Assistant for rapid prototyping.

Lead a 'Design Skills For HRI' Workshop HRI 2016 - Christchurch, New Zealand

Lead a 'Human Centred Design' Workshop

CuriousU Design Festival - University of Twente